A Bride for Christmas is a romance, comedy, tv
movie film directed by Gary Yates.
Bride-to-be Jessie Patterson calls off her third
engagement - during the ceremony!
She swears off serious relationships, until she meets
and is pursued by Aiden MacTiernan.
Aiden, on the other hand, has bet his friends he is marriage material, and
can find a fiancé in the four weeks leading up to Christmas.
When Jessie and Aiden begin to fall for each other, Jessie must decide if she is ready for serious
love, and Aiden must decide if his bet is worth risking his relationship with Jessie.
Jessie, played by Arielle Kebbel.
Mike, played by Sage Brocklebank.
Matt, played by Peter Benson.
Marcie, played by Jordana Largy.
Patty, played by Chelsey Reist.
Aiden, played by Andrew W. Walker.
Corpse Bride (also known as Tim Burton's Corpse Bride) is a 2005 stop-motion animated musical Gothic fantasy film
directed by Mike Johnson and Tim Burton and written by John August, Caroline Thompson, and Pamela Pettler.
Set in an English village, Corpse Bride stars Johnny Depp as the voice of
Victor, while Helena Bonham Carter voices Emily, the title character.
An international co-production between the United States and United Kingdom, produced by Tim
Burton Productions and Laika Entertainment, and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, Corpse Bride is the first stop-motion feature film directed by Burton after previously
producing The Nightmare Before Christmas (1993) and James and the Giant Peach (1996).
Corpse Bride drew inspiration from a 17th-century Jewish folktale, which Joe Ranft
introduced to Burton while they were finishing The Nightmare Before Christmas.
Work on the film started in November 2003 while Burton was wrapping up Big Fish.
His next live-action feature, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory,
was produced simultaneously with Corpse Bride.
Production of the stop-motion animation feature took
place at 3 Mills Studios in London.
It was shot with Canon EOS-1D Mark II digital SLRs, rather than the 35
mm film cameras used for The Nightmare Before Christmas.
Burton immediately brought regular collaborators
Depp, Carter and Danny Elfman aboard.
Corpse Bride is dedicated to executive producer Ranft, who
died a month before the film's release.
Corpse Bride premiered at the 62nd Venice International Film Festival on September
7, 2005, and was released in theaters on September 23 in the U.S.
and on October 13 in the U.K.
to critical and commercial success.
The film was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 78th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of bet, wedding, christmas.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.